《纸牌屋》前情提要...
Previously on House of Cards...
关键问题在于  白宫是否也在某种程度上卷入其中
The issue at stake is whether the White House was in any way involved.
单是为来自中国的政治献金洗白就是违法的
Just the act of laundering Chinese contributions is illegal.
道格拉斯·斯坦普  你的幕僚长
Douglas Stamper, your chief of staff.
这是7月14日他在拉尼根的赌场
This is him at Lanagin's casino July 14th.
他们有证据证明道格出现在不该出现的地方
They have evidence of Doug being where he shouldn't have been.
这是能招致弹劾的罪行
We're talking about impeachable offenses...
-完全不会 先生    -你的幕僚长...
- Not at all, sir...    - Your chief of staff was...
你害怕了  我看得出来
You're scared. I can tell.
你让我说什么  我就说什么
I'll say whatever you want me to say.
她可能会起诉你
She could indict you.
幕僚就是做这个的
That's what having a staff is for.
强如阿喀琉斯  也终被踵上一箭毙命
Even Achilles was only as strong as his heel.
他们声音很响  但我们要发出更高的声音
They're loud,but I think we need to be louder.
如果法案真能进入辩论 我不会单单退出
If the bill goes to the floor as is,I won't just bow out.
我会积极反对
I'll actively fight it.
要我说  她也背叛了自己的国家
If you ask me,she's betraying her country, too.
多线作战  雷米 必须得是杰姬·夏普
Multiple fronts, Remy. Has to be Jackie Sharp.
-那我就是对的    -关于什么
- Then I was right.   - About what?
你根本不在乎我
How little I meant.
她已经会见了一半的国会议员  这女人是要见血
She's interviewed half of Congress.That woman's after blood.
他是在担心他的婚姻咨询 他也该担心
He's worried about his marriage counseling, as he should be.
如果你是在担心你的婚姻咨询 你不必担心
If you're worried about your marriage counseling, you shouldn't be.
你得想想这件事的后果
Imagine the fallout.
有个地址老是出现
This one address keeps popping up.
-安德伍德吗    -是总统
- Underwood?    - The President.
你讲的是法律
You're parsing the law.
我讲的则是精神层面的法则
And I'm talking about a spiritual code.
保密协议是一份契约
Confidentiality is a covenant.
不仅在我和接受我咨询的人之间成立
Not only between myself and those I counsel,
在我自己和上帝之间也成立
but also between myself and the Lord.
拉金博士  我现在重点关注的是洗钱案
Dr. Larkin, my chief focus here is the money laundering.
如果总统先生提到过冯山德
If the President brought up Xander Feng,
雷蒙德·塔斯克  还有阿道希赌场
Raymond Tusk, the Adohi Casino--
不管重点是什么
It doesn't matter what the focus is.
我都不能向你透露私人谈话的内容
I can't share anything we discussed privately.
宗教指导受法律保护
Religious guidance is protected.
但你也提供专业的心理咨询
But you were also conducting professional therapy.
这我从未承认过
I never claimed that.
基斯先生及太太已经证实了
Mr. And Mrs. Keith confirmed as much.
我们是去了他们家
We were at their house.
但他们并没有参与谈话
But they didn't participate in any of our conversations.
他们又怎么可能知道
So how would they know?
你是说你只提供宗教咨询吗
So you're saying you only gave religious counsel?
这是我对我工作的理解
That's how I choose to interpret it.
总统夫妇从没去过你的教堂
The President and his wife have never once attended your church.
甚至都和你不是一个教派的
They're not even the same denomination.
无关紧要
Irrelevant.
法律上可紧要得很
Not legally speaking.
我绝对能说服法官发传票给你
I'm certain I can convince a judge to issue a subpoena
因为你并非总统夫妇正式的宗教导师
on the grounds that you weren't their legitimate spiritual advisor.
那是你的特权
Which is your prerogative.
但我会上诉  我肯定会
But I can appeal. And I would.
那你一定败诉
You'd lose.
除非对方放弃保密权利
The only circumstance by which I would talk
我绝不会回答你的问题
is if someone personally waived their privilege.
否则我宁可被判蔑视法庭
Otherwise I'd rather face contempt of court.
这事关道德
It's a matter of ethics.
总统先生  你又把沙袋挪回来了
Mr. President. Ah, you brought it back in.
弗洛伊德·梅威瑟[著名拳击手]今早来白宫参观
Floyd Mayweather visited the White House this morning.
我觉得他看见这个肯定很兴奋
I thought he'd get a kick out of it.
他没打几拳
Did he have a go at it?
他打了套组合拳  我都担心把沙袋打爆了
He threw a combination I thought would bust the stitching loose.
那场面一定很好看
Well, that must have been a treat to watch.
他告诉我  这不仅仅是力量的问题
He was telling me it's not just about the power.
比他更有力量的拳手不少
Plenty of boxers are more powerful than he is.
关键是他的战术  他的准头和速度
No, it's his tactics, his precision, his speed.
最重要的一点  就是他的反击
Most important? His counter punch.
他躲闪腾挪  选择最完美的时机一拳制胜
He dances and dodges and then picks the perfect moment to strike.
听着耳熟吗
Does that sound familiar?
什么意思  先生
How do you mean, sir?
你送我这个沙袋  作为友谊的表示
You gave this to me as a gesture of friendship.
但我现在看着它  却感受不到友谊
When I look at this now, I don't see friendship.
我看到的是算计
I see calculation.
你算计我  弗兰克
You set me up, Frank.
什么
What?
你的私下接触  还有特别检察官
Your back channeling. The special prosecutor.
再想想雷蒙德  琳达  还有吉姆·马修斯
When I think about Raymond, about Linda, about Jim Matthews...
你想错了  先生
You are wrong, sir.
这是邓巴就婚姻咨询问的问题
Questions from Dunbar about the marriage counseling.
"那是大海里的一根针  还不是邓巴要找的那根"
"It's a needle in the haystack she's not trying to find."
这是你的原话  她还真就捞着了
That's what you said. Well, she found the needle.
我非常震惊  我绝没
I am shocked, sir. I -- I never --
你震惊才怪  你想削弱我的权威
Like hell you are. You want to deminish me.
削弱你的权威
Diminish you?
为你2016年挑战我打基础
Laying the groundwork for a challenge in 2016.
恕我无礼  但你这论调太荒唐了
I am sorry to have to say this, sir, but you are being ludicrous.
你真以为我瞎了吗
Do you really think I'm so blind?
从没有哪个副总统挑战过在位总统
A vice president has never challenged a sitting president.
你往上爬的过程中已经做过不少别人不会做的事了
You've climbed the ladder doing things other men would never do.
全都是为了服务于你和本党的利益
Always in service to you and the party.
交出行程记录是你的主意
It was you idea to hand over those logs.
是你让白宫和中国扯上了关系  还有赌场
You connected the White House to China, the casino --
是雷蒙德·塔斯克让我们与中国和赌场扯上了关系
Raymond Tusk entangled us with China and the casino.
要不是我及时干预
And if I hadn't intervened --
你没有弗洛伊德那套腾挪的本事  我识破你了
You can't dodge and duck like Floyd. I've learned your moves now.
当了总统就易多疑  你别这样  先生
This office breeds paranoia. Don't give into it, sir.
要不是会引人非议  我就会要求你辞职了
I'd ask for your resignation if it wouldn't make things worse.
但从此刻开始  我不想听你的任何建议
But from this moment forward, I don't want to hear your voice,
也不想看见你
I don't want to see your face.
再让我看见你  我就让你吃不了兜着走
And if I do, I will put you on your god damn back.
我被驱逐了  我成功将总统和其他人隔开
Exile. I've managed to isolate the president from everyone.
包括我自己
Including myself.
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译 章鱼X   卫老哥   艾瑞卡
翻译 卢克·天意   冬麟   某豚   香茗小焙
蓝光版调整  timhal@HDWinG字幕组   后期 饿得慌
顾问 老杜   校对 草草   总监 草草
本字幕由YYETS翻译 HDWinG字幕组修正 请勿去掉制作者信息
《纸牌屋》
第二季  第十二集
"夏普女众议员淋漓尽致地展现了
"Congresswoman Sharp is a  perfect example
军方是如何将我们洗脑
of how the military brainwashes us
从而绝对服从党派路线的
into never questioning the party line.
她对法案的反对是可耻的
Her opposition to the bill is disgraceful.
这会使数以千计的男性和女性
It will cost thousands of men and women
得不到他们应得的公正
the justice they deserve,
甚至会毁掉一些人的生活"
and some of them their lives."
这都是梅根·汉纳希的话  他们有失公正
Those are Megan Hennessey's words. They're biased.
这是克莱尔教她说的  汉纳希不过是传声筒
They're Claire's words. Hennessey's just the mouthpiece.
为什么文中还说我拒绝置评
Why does it say here that I declined to comment?
你说过  会惹麻烦的事能躲就躲
You said you didn't want to kick up dust if we could avoid it.
这是《纽约时代杂志》  你应该告诉我的
It's the New York fucking Times. You should've let me know.
是我的决定  我承担责任
That was my call. I'll take the blame.
查明汉纳希接下来会在哪里出现
Find out when Hennessey's next appearance is.
我要搞垮这个婊子
I'm gonna beat this bitch down.
我知道她针对你  但是针对她的话...
I know she went after you, but going after her is --
不是她  是克莱尔·安德伍德
Not her. Claire Underwood.
我知道加勒特可能会产生误解
I understand how Garrett might misconstrue things,
毕竟现在他压力很大
given the pressure he's under.
但你肯定不会相信吧
But you can't honestly believe it yourself.
我已经不知道该相信什么了
I don't know what to believe anymore.
弗兰西斯非常沮丧  他只是想帮忙
Francis is devastated. All he wants to do is help,
但他觉得自己受到了冤枉
but he feels like he's being unfairly accused.
我也不想相信  克莱尔  但加勒特确信不疑
I don't want to believe it, Claire, but Garrett is convinced.
你能跟他谈谈吗
Will you talk to him?
我现在得集中精力维护我的家庭
I have to concentrate on keeping my family together right now.
而不是跟他争吵关于...
Not getting into arguments over --
如果弗兰西斯真有什么图谋
If Francis were really up to something,
那他怎么不直接把咨询的事告诉邓巴
don't you think he would have told Dunbar about the therapy?
他逼我们交出记录就等于那么做了
He basically did by forcing us to hand over the logs.
那是你丈夫的决定
Your husband chose to hand them over.
如果他拒绝  弗兰西斯是不会逼他的
If he'd said no, Francis wouldn't have pressed the issue.
我不想跟你争这个  克莱尔
I don't want to debate this with you, Claire.
我只求你好好想想这件事  特莉莎
All I'm asking is that you really think this through, Tricia.
他现在跟你在一起吗
Is he with you right now?
谁
Who?
弗兰克
Frank.
不  只有我和你
No. It's just you and me.
我要挂电话了
I want to get off the phone.
拜托你跟加勒特谈谈好吗
Will you please talk to Garrett?
再见  克莱尔
Goodbye, Claire.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我不觉得她会抛开丈夫站在我这边
I don't think she's going to side with me instead of her husband.
除了跟你  特莉莎还跟别人说过阿普唑仑的事吗
Did Tricia tell anyone else about the Xanax besides you?
镇静抗焦虑药
应该没有  她对此非常敏感
I doubt she would. She's very sensitive about it.
她要是跟别人说过  我们就可以把消息传出去
If she'd only told someone else, then we could just leak it.
但是这太明显了
But it'll be too obvious.
医生
The doctor.
他在保护他们  他什么都不会说的
He's protecting them. He won't say anything.
除非他们放弃保密特权
Unless they waive the privilege.
那对他们可没有好处
They have absolutely nothing to gain by that.
但是对我们有
But we do.
你得去见塔斯克
You have to meet with Tusk.
我背叛了他  他为什么还要见我
Why would he talk to me after I back-stabbed him?
正因为如此他才会见你
That's precisely why he'll talk to you.
我不能去圣路易斯  你知道的...
Well, I can't go to St. Louis. You know --
塔斯克会来东部  你要做的就是找到他
Tusk will come east. Your job is to get in the same room with him.
-什么计划    -雷米·丹顿
- What's the play?   - Remy Danton.
去  让杜兰特来找我
Go. Get me Durant, in person.
我来安排
I'll set it up.
道格  一定确保其他方面我们万无一失
And Doug? Let's make sure we're airtight on everything else.
不能有软肋
No Achilles heel.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
"灾难来临了"  用混乱对抗混乱的人说
"Cry, 'Havoc,'" Said he who fought chaos with chaos,
"让我们释放战争恶魔"
"And let slip the dogs of war."
失约  数周不联络  你知道规矩
Missed appointments. No contact in weeks. You know the rules.
我要跟格林特工谈
I'd like to speak to Agent Green, please.
你想干什么
What are you up to?
给格林打电话
Put Green on the fucking line, please.
不管你想说什么  都可以跟我说
Anything you have to say, you can discuss it with me.
我要说的事远远超出了你的级别
What I have to say is way above your pay grade.
我怎么关掉这破玩意
Where do I turn off this shit?
看看左边的那块屏幕
Look at the other screen, to the left.
这是什么
What is this?
这是美国电话电报公司八个数据中心的访问网格
That is the access grid to all eight of AT&T's data centers.
所以你还是解开手铐
So what do you say you un-cuff me
然后告诉格林特工我在等他的电话吧
and tell Agent Green I'll be waiting for his call?
我正在试图修复与中国的关系
I'm trying to repair relations with China.
给冯政治庇护就是一记耳光
Giving Feng asylum would be a slap in the face.
加勒特有麻烦  他得表现出决心
Garrett's in trouble. He needs to appear resolute.
我们的总统有多强  我们就有多强
We're only as strong as the president we serve.
我们必须拯救他
We have to rescue him.
你怎么能确定他的证词不会扯上白宫
How can you be sure his testimony won't implicate the White House?
他知道谁有奶  谁是娘
He knows where his bread is buttered.
你这不是要拯救总统
This isn't about you saving the president.
-当然是    -这不是第一次了  弗兰克
- Of course it is.   - We've been down this road before, Frank.
迈克尔·科恩  亚当·嘉乐威
Michael Kern, Adam Galloway.
我想当国务卿
I wanted to become secretary of state
是为了进行有成效的外交
in order to engage in productive diplomacy,
而不是全职损失控制
not full-time damage control.
所以我们要让加勒特回到正轨
Which is why we have to put Garrett back on his feet.
你是想让他脱轨吧  弗兰克
You want him on his ass, Frank.
是总统这么跟你说的吗
Is this what the president told you?
他现在太多疑了  凯茜
He's paranoid, Cathy.
他想让大家跟我反目
He's trying to turn people against me.
是你自己的行为让大家跟你反目
You're turning them against yourself.
你在要求我坑害总统
You're asking me to undermine the president.
好吧
All right.
假如总统对我的指责属实
Let's say that what the President has accused me of is true.
这就真的很糟吗  考虑一下这么做的结果
Would that be so bad? If taken to its conclusion?
对你没有好处吗
Wouldn't you stand to benefit?
对国家没有好处吗
Wouldn't the country?
我不想牵扯进去
I don't want anything to do with this.
就再做一次  凯茜
Just one more time, Cathy.
别去管那些条条框框
Let's unshackle ourselves.
机会只有一次  冯先生
This is a one-time offer, Mr. Feng.
我要白纸黑字写下来  不加任何条件
I would need it in writing. Open-ended, no restrictions.
法定豁免权也是一样
The same goes for legal immunity.
首先我要确认
First I need to know whether or not
你是否通过拉尼根的赌场洗钱
you funneled money through Lanagin's casino.
不  等我安全抵达美国
No, no. I will speak freely once I've arrived safely
我才会全盘托出
in the United States.
除非你现在就能提供确凿证据
Unless you provide valuable evidence now,
司法部长不会答应任何豁免权
the attorney general will not grant immunity on any level.
我在中国已经全部否认了这些指控
I've denied these allegations in China.
我的敌人想置我于死地
My enemies want me dead.
你这是逼我给他们证据
You're asking me to give them confirmation.
作为回报  我们会给你提供避难所
And we're giving you safe haven in return.
我在迪拜已经有避难所了
I already have safe haven in Dubai.
你在那里的庇护所只是暂时的
Your asylum there is only temporary.
我们给你提供的是永久身份
We're offering you permanent status.
我相信他们也会给我永久身份
I'm confident that they will grant me permanent status.
是外交部长亲口跟你说的吗
Did you hear that directly from the Minister of Foreign Affairs?
因为我刚跟他谈过
Because I just spoke to him.
现在你连护照都没有
Right now you are a man without a passport.
北京方面还没查封的资产
Whatever assets Beijing hasn't seized are frozen
也都被所有和中美关系紧密的国家冻结了
in every country with close ties to the United Sates or China,
基本上是全世界所有国家
which is just about every country in the world.
你想要自由和金钱  我们想要信息
You want your freedom and fortune. We want information.
冯先生
Mr. Feng?
你想知道什么
What do you need to know?
向我证实确实有洗钱行为
Confirm for me the existence of a money-laundering scheme.
是的  我们用赌场来掩饰外资流入
Yes. We used the casino to mask foreign contributions.
好的
All right.
你们中谁跟我讲讲这是怎么回事
One of you want to tell me what this is all about?
你必须得遵从
You have to comply.
你是说我得出席
You mean I have to show up.
除非我们上诉
Unless we appeal.
我们会输
We'd lose.
她要不是证据确凿
She wouldn't have issued the subpoena
也不会传唤我
unless she had something substantial.
我同意
I agree.
这就是为什么我觉得你该去
Which is why I think you should go
并拒不解释
and plead the Fifth.
你觉得她手上有什么
What do you think she has?
我不想妄加推断
I don't want to speculate.
老天  我付给你们六个一天的钱
God damn it, I pay the six of you more in one day
比供个孩子上大学都多
than it costs to put a kid through college.
我请你们是要你们比我知道得多
And I pay you to know more than I do.
她问询时说的对我们会很有帮助
Her line of questioning will tell us a lot.
万一她真要提出指控  我们可以据此准备辩护
We can use that to prepare our defense in case there's an indictment.
我什么时候走
When do I have to go?
你的会面是在后天
Your interview is the day after next.
48小时
48 hours?
发动不了吗
Having trouble starting it?
是的  可能电池没电了吧
Yeah. I think the battery might be dead.
如果你想试试跨接启动  我有电线
I have some cables if you want to try and jump it.
这真的不麻烦吗
You sure you don't mind?
一点也不
Not at all.
好吧  你真是太好了
All right. It's really nice of you.
开引擎盖  我把我车开过来
Pop your hood. I'll bring my car around.
好
Sure.
这位是彼得  他开车送我回来的
This is Peter. He's the guy who drove me back.
这些要放哪
Where do you want these?
我来拿  谢谢
I'll take 'em. Thanks.
瑞秋  是吗
Rachel, right?
是的
Yeah.
丽萨说你俩是室友
Lisa said you two were roommates.
要我给你拿点什么  来杯水吗
Can I get you something? A glass of water?
不用  谢谢  我得走了
No, thanks. I should really get going.
好吧  太谢谢你了
All right. I can't thank you enough.
不客气  希望车能修好
My pleasure. Good luck with the car.
谢谢
Thanks.
希望只是电池没电  晚安
I hope it's only a dead battery. Have a good night.
我们应该给他些钱
We should give him some money.
彼得
Peter.
她得离开
She needs to be gone.
你跟我说她可以留下的
Y-- you told me she could stay.
我改主意了
I changed my mind.
你说你不在乎她在不在这儿
But you said you didn't care if she was here --
我不需要解释什么
I don't need to explain myself.
你受不了了  是吗
You can't stand it, can you?
受不了我爱上了别人
The idea that I might actually love somebody.
受不了我生命中除了你还有别人
That I might have somebody in my life who isn't you.
如果你在乎她  就让她走  瑞秋
If you care about her, make it happen, Rachel.
没事吧
Is everything okay?
没事  告诉你朋友我不会要钱的
Yeah. You need to tell your friend that I won't take any money.
我很乐意帮忙
I was happy to do it.
我们都需要好心人帮忙
We all need a good Samaritan every now and again.
麦金尼斯将军被判处
Did you feel justice was served
四十年有期徒刑时  你觉得正义得到伸张了吗
when General McGinnis got sentenced to 40 years?
梅根·汉纳希  反性侵活动分子
就他的罪行而言  正义是得以伸张了
Yes, as far as his crimes go.
但还有成千的服役士兵没有...
But not for thousands of servicemen and --
抱歉  抱歉打断你的讲话
I'm -- I'm sor-- I'm sorry to interrupt.
我的制作人告诉我
m-- my producer is telling me that,
杰奎琳·夏普刚打电话来
Jacqueline Sharp has called in,
众议院多数党党鞭  议员女士  您在吗
the house majority whip. C-- congresswoman, are you there?
是的  我在  克里斯  谢谢你接我的电话
Yes, I'm here, Chris. And thank you for taking my call.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你好  梅根
Hello, Megan.
议员女士
Congresswoman.
首先  作为一名老兵
First of all, as a veteran like yourself,
我想感谢你对国家的贡献
I want to thank you for your service to our country.
这是责任  无需感谢
Duty doesn't require thanks.
我很高兴你提到责任这个话题
I'm glad you brought up duty,
因为你最近将它称之为洗脑
because you recently equated it with brainwashing.
那不是我的本意
That's not what I meant.
你说"紧跟党派路线"
You said "Toeing the party line."
电话连线  杰奎琳·夏普议员  众议院多数党党鞭
我的本意是文化和体系是...
What I meant was that the culture and the system is one that --
我不是打电话来和你辩论的  梅根
I didn't call to argue with you, Megan.
恰恰相反
The opposite.
我们要解决这个问题  就必须找到共同点
We can't fix this problem until we find some common ground.
你不觉得吗
Wouldn't you agree?
就我来看这个问题没有妥协空间
There is no middle ground as far as I'm concerned.
军队需要改变
The military needs to change --
你和我都曾经在军中服役
Can't we agree that you and I served
以保护人民自由辩论的权利
so that we could protect open debate,
而这正是民主的基础  你说不是吗
which is the very bedrock of democracy?
理论上是的  但这不是我要说的
Yes, in theory, but that's not what I'm talking about.
不是理论上  是实际上
Not in theory. In reality.
勇敢的人为了这份自由不惜牺牲生命
Brave men and women die fighting for that freedom.
勇敢的涵义就是为那些和你意见相左的人
The meaning of bravery is fighting for the freedom
也同样享有自由而战斗
of those with whom you disagree.
当然  但我们回到真正的话题上来好吗
Sure, but let's get back to the issue here.
我认为不勇敢的人是克莱尔·安德伍德
What I don't think is brave is Claire Underwood
逃避这场辩论  找你替她进行这场斗争
dodging this debate and having you fight this battle for her instead.
不是这样的
That's not true.
那我为什么在和你而不是她谈话  这是她的法案
Then why am I talking to you instead of her? It's her bill.
不只是她  是我们共同的成果
It's not just hers. It's all of ours.
可是你勇敢地说出来了
Except one of you is brave enough to say it,
而她却是个懦夫
and the other is a coward.
安德伍德夫人勇敢地
Mrs. Underwood was brave enough
在全国性电视节目上承认她...
to go on national television and admit that she --
没错  但那之后她去哪了
Yeah, and where has she been since then?
应付丑闻  躲避媒体
Deflecting scandal and hiding from the press.
梅根  你在《纽约时代杂志》上说我可耻
You called me disgraceful in The New York Times, Megan,
你当然有这个权利
and you have every right.
但我也有权说  安德伍德夫人是可耻的
But I also have the right to say that Mrs. Underwood is disgraceful,
因为没有什么
because there is nothing
比当逃兵更可耻
more disgraceful than running from a battle.
梅根  我们根本没有...
Megan? That is -- we're not even...
我们马上回来
We'll be right back.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去国会
To the Capitol.
冯提到我或总统了吗
Did Feng mention either me or the president?
邓巴不肯说
Dunbar wouldn't say.
但冯确认了洗钱行为
But the fact that Feng confirmed the money laundering
这足以让白宫更受关注
increases focus on the White House.
反正我们是清白的
Well, as long as we're innocent, which we are.
雷蒙德·塔斯克被传唤了
Raymond Tusk has been subpoenaed.
你为什么找我们见面  比尔
Why did you ask for this meeting, Bill?
就为了向我们通报消息吗
Just keeping us in the loop?
是你让国务卿杜兰特给予冯政治庇护吗
Did you encourage Secretary Durant to offer Feng asylum?
比尔  我的天呐
Bill, for god sakes.
总统也可能问我这个问题
The president could have asked me that question himself.
作为白宫顾问  这是我的责任
As the White House counsel, it is my responsibility --
不  我没有
No, I did not.
那么这是杜兰特自己的主意喽
So you're saying Durant acted of her own accord.
我不知道她的动机是什么
I have no idea what her motivations were.
我和总统一样感到震惊
I'm just as shocked as the president
她居然没经过他本人允许就擅自而为了
that she would have gone through with this without his direct approval.
还有一个问题我想和你谈谈
There's another matter I'd like to discuss.
如果可以  最好只跟你谈
Privately, if we could.
让我们单独待会儿
Just give us a few moments.
-咨询    -是的
- The therapy.- Yes.
具体说  就是放弃保密权
To be specific, the confidentiality waiver.
冯的证词把我们推到一个非常尴尬的位置上
Feng's testimony puts us in a very awkward position.
我们现在面对放弃保密权的极大压力
We're under a great deal of pressure to waive the privilege.
如果不放弃  就相当于总统
If we don't, it implies that the president
承认了他没做过的事
may have confessed to things he didn't.
邓巴只是在瞎猜  别让步
Dunbar is just grasping. Don't give in.
我不想让步
I don't want to.
但拉金宗教指导保密协议的说法并不可靠
But Larkin's argument for spiritual confidentiality is shaky at best.
我们想控制事态的发展
We want to control how this thing plays out.
我能帮什么忙
How can I help?
我们要确保不会再节外生枝
We need to know if anyone else might pop out of the woodwork.
我没对任何人说过  克莱尔也没说过
Well, I haven't mentioned it to anyone, and neither has Claire.
我不会辜负总统对我的信任
I would never betray the president's trust like that.
谢谢你抽出时间
Thank you for your time.
告诉总统  我非常难过
Tell the president it saddens me that
我们现在只能通过律师交流
we now have to communicate through lawyers.
要是他想亲自
I will make myself available
和我谈谈  我会抽出时间的
if he wants to discuss any of this in person.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
梅根的话太过分了
What Megan said was offensive.
她不该质疑你的品行
She shouldn't have questioned your character.
那都是精心准备的谈话要点  而且不是她准备的
Those were talking points. Carefully crafted, and not by her.
我不是来挑衅的  杰姬  我是来解决问题的
I'm not here to pick a fight, Jackie. I'm here to end one.
只要法案进行投票  这事就会结束
Well, it'll end soon enough when the bill goes to the floor.
不会进行投票的
It won't go to the floor.
我跟艾琳·布鲁克斯谈过了  我要撤销法案
I've spoken to Elaine Brooks and I'm withdrawing the bill.
你说的有一定道理
What you said had some truth.
之前你提出
And early on you offered
我们一起找个折中的办法
to sit down with me and find a middle ground.
我那时拒绝了你
I decided to draw a line in the sand.
但勇敢的做法应该是
And the braver thing would've been for me
收起我的骄傲  跟你好好谈
to swallow my pride and sit down with you.
如果你还愿谈  我想重新开始
If you're still open to that, I'd love to start over.
你和弗兰克在打什么主意吗
Are you and Frank up to something?
一项能通过的法案
A passable bill.
他让南茜监视我  他把我的个人生活搞得
He had Nancy spy on me. He brought my personal life into --
弗兰西斯习惯了事事得逞
Francis is used to getting his way.
他会不惜一切确保成功
And he'll do anything to make sure he does,
尤其是对我重要的事
especially if it's something important to me.
我不知道  克莱尔  我很怀疑
I don't know, Claire. I'm skeptical.
之前那样对待你  我们深表歉意
We're deeply sorry for the way we've treated you
我们想重拾失去的信任
and we want to rebuild the trust we've lost.
你觉得这可能吗
Do you think that's possible?
很抱歉突然这么来了  我打过电话
I'm sorry to ambush you. I tried calling.
你不能这么对我  克莱尔
You can't do this to me, Claire.
我说得很清楚  我必须尊重加勒特的意愿
I was very clear that I have to respect Garrett's wishes --
不是那个  是性侵犯法案
Not that. The sexual assault bill.
不会进行投票了
It's not going to a vote.
议长从日程中删除了吗
Did the speaker remove it from the docket?
不  是我撤掉了  我刚跟杰姬谈过
No. I did. I just spoke to Jackie.
是因为她那样说你吗
This is because of what she said about you?
我主要是担心她接下来会不会对付你
My main concern is that she doesn't come after you next.
你和加勒特接受调查期间绝不能发生这种事
Not while you and Garrett are going through the investigation.
我想来告诉你
I thought you should be aware
因为我知道这项法案对你有多重要
because I know how much this bill meant to you.
你为法案投入了那么多
All the work you've put in.
我们都投入过  但我们要通过杰姬的法案
That we've put in. But we'll pass Jackie's version,
迈出这一小步  循序渐进
take this baby step, and build on it.
法案的事我很失望
I'm disappointed about the bill,
但不得不说  我松了口气
but I have to say, I'm relieved.
你还好吧
How are you holding up?
你听说凯瑟琳做了什么吗  许诺冯政治避难
Did you hear what Catherine did? Giving Feng asylum?
不可原谅
Inexcusable.
加勒特气疯了  他觉得走投无路
Garrett's beside himself. He feels cornered,
这下我们除了放弃保密权别无选择
like we have no choice but to waive the privileges now.
药物的事呢
But what about the medication?
可不是啊  我不该说的
I know. I shouldn't be sharing this.
不说了  你该走了
We don't have to talk about it. You should go.
我知道你日程排得很满
I know you have a packed schedule.
谢谢你这么做
Thank you for doing this.
我只是在走廊里单独找上了她
All I had to do was get her alone in a hallway.
我是说杰姬那边
I meant with Jackie.
我们要分清轻重缓急
We have our priorities.
我知道做这样的放弃并不容易
Well, I know it isn't easy to let go of something like that.
答应我一件事
Promise me something.
你说吧
Anything.
我不能一个人住在这房子里
I can't live in this house alone.
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
你是这么说  但这事可能事与愿违
You say that, but this could all backfire.
雷蒙德肯定会拒不解释
Raymond will plead the Fifth.
如果他提到我  便是承认有罪了
If he names me, it's an admission of his own wrongdoing.
我更担心加勒特
I'm more worried about Garrett.
你制造了一个有力的对手
You've made a powerful enemy.
我们比他们强
We're stronger than they are.
可他仍然是总统
And he's still the president.
我向你保证  你被迫做出的一切牺牲之中
I promise you, of all of the sacrifices that you've had to make,
绝不会包括与一名罪犯离婚
divorcing a convict will not be one of them.
我们不能放弃保密权  加勒特
We can't waive the privileges, Garrett.
我们没别的选择了  冯承认了那笔钱
Well, we don't have a choice anymore. Feng confirmed the money.
在电话上承认的  不是当面正式承认的
Over the phone. Not in a formal interview.
解除对他的庇护  送他回去
Rescind the asylum. Send him back --
妨碍司法公正
Obstruction of justice.
嘉利克这么说的吗
Is that what Galich said?
别人肯定会这么想
Definitely how it would be perceived.
我们任何不配合调查的举动
And anything we do that looks like a failure to cooperate
都会加重他们的猜疑
amplifies that perception.
我只是不想公开我们的婚姻问题
I just don't want our marriage put on display.
邓巴会问我是否提及过中国  我没有
Look, Dunbar'll ask if I brought up China. I didn't.
拉金能证明我的清白
So Larkin can only help to exonerate me.
如果婚姻咨询最终进入报告  也无所谓
And if the marriage counseling ends up in the report, so be it.
我们能渡过这个难关
We can survive that.
但他给我们开了处方药
But he prescribed us medication.
不算是我们
Technically not us.
你在吃我的药  加勒特
You took mine, Garrett.
拉金知道你会吃才给我开的药
Larkin wrote the prescription to me knowing you would.
等等  你提过了  处方药的事
Wait, wait, have you mentioned it? The medication?
跟克莱尔吗
Claire?
对不起  我只能跟她倾诉
I'm sorry. But she's the only person I can talk to
只有她能理解
who really understands what it's like --
那我们更要放弃保密权了
Oh, all the more reason we have to waive the privilege.
如果他们泄露出去  就由不得我们做主了
If they leak this, we can't control the information.
克莱尔不会那么做的
Claire wouldn't do that.
不要小看她
Don't underestimate her.
他们要是真准备这么做  现在不早做了
If they were going to, don't you think they would have done it by now?
她为了减少我们的负担  放弃了性侵法案
She dropped the sexual assault bill to reduce pressure on us.
她也许是这么跟你说的
That may have been what she told you.
他们什么都不会说的
They're not going to say anything.
我求你了  加勒特
I'm begging you, Garrett.
不要放弃保密权
Don't waive the privilege.
我们谈论的事太私密了
The things we talked about were so intimate.
如果孩子们看到
Imagine if the kids --
我知道  但是特莉莎
I know. But Tricia --
我们竞选的时候
When we ran,
我知道我们的生活将被人仔细审视
I knew every aspect of our lives would be under scrutiny.
但我觉得我们至少还能保护这个
But I thought we could protect at least this.
发生在这里的事
What happens in here.
我会不惜一切保护我们
I'll protect us. Whatever I have to do.
你要相信我
You have to believe that.
我们检查了USB软件狗
We checked the USB dongle.
你声称感染了信息中心的代码不在里面
The code you're claiming infected the data center isn't there.
我设计那段代码一到达服务器便自我删除
I programmed the code to self-erase as soon as it hit the server.
在卢卡斯被捕之前就不见了
It was gone before Lucas was in cuffs.
你信不过我
You don't believe me?
这可是世上最复杂的防火墙之一
This is one of the most sophisticated firewalls in the world.
就算真的进去了  也破坏不了
Even if your code did get in there, you couldn't break it down.
你妻子手机的运营商就是他们公司
Your wife uses AT&T.
她情人也是
So does her lover.
什么
What?
她现在就在那儿  乔纳森·坎普
She's over there right now. Jonathan Kemp.
她的脊椎按摩师  对吗
It's her chiropractor, right?
想看看他们互发的短信吗
Want to see their texts to each other?
不想
No.
看来你早就知道了
Oh, I see you already know.
我理解你不想把事情闹大
I don't blame you for not making a fuss,
毕竟孩子们还在家里
what with the kids still at home.
但你让我的代码进了那扇门
But you walked my code right through that door.
进入了三千两百万人的手机里
Into 32 million people's phones.
这都怪你
And that's on you.
联调局也罪责难逃  这会闹得很难看
And it's on the FBI. And it is a shit-storm
让联调局面临国会的调查
that will bring the Bureau right in front of Congress.
所以你告诉我  平息这一切要多大代价
So you tell me: How much is making that disappear worth?
你面临一百年的监禁
You have a hundred years hanging over your head.
敲诈联调局对你没好处
Extorting the FBI won't help you.
是道格拉斯·斯坦普让你陷害卢卡斯·古德温的吗
Did Douglas Stamper tell you to set up Lucas Goodwin?
反恐主管
Counter-Terrorism Director.
跟白宫联络官相比真是一步登天
That's a big step up from White House Liaison.
-我认为你背后有推手    -胡说
- I think you had a helping hand.   - Not true.
继续编  但以下是我的要求
Keep lying. Meanwhile, here's what I want.
第一  我不再是你的走狗了
One, I'm no longer your bitch.
第二  撤销对我的所有指控
Two, all of my charges are dropped.
第三  撤销所有对巴利特·布朗的指控
Three, all of Barrett Brown's charges are dropped.
这得看联邦检察官的
That's up to the U.S. Attorney.
你去想办法
Figure it out.
如果我听得没错
If I'm hearing you correctly,
你是想要拉金的证词
you'd like to keep Larkin's testimony
侧重在洗钱上
focused on the money laundering.
而我从来没提过  因为我毫不知情
Which I never brought up, because I knew nothing about it.
但你担心其他的事  私人的事
But your concern is other matters. Private matters.
这些和调查无关
Which are irrelevant to the investigation.
我不能阻止邓巴问问题
I can't prevent Dunbar from asking what she's gonna ask.
当然不能
Of course not.
我最多只能去拜托拉金博士
The most I can do is ask Dr. Larkin
跟他对下部分问题的回答
how he would respond to certain questions.
但他很聪明  会明白我的目的
But he's a smart man. He'll understand what I'm getting at.
这路子合法吗
And this approach keeps us within the law?
没有干扰证词吗
We're not tampering with testimony?
界线很模糊  但我会确保合法
It's a fine line. But I'll stay on the right side of it.
他不见我  弗兰克  就像他对你一样
He shut me out, Frank. Just like he did with you.
我的副国务卿被委派了全权外交权
My undersecretary has been assigned full diplomatic authority.
暂时的挫折  凯茜  我到哪你到哪
A temporary setback, Cathy. Where I go, you go.
现在总统正在战况室
At this very moment, the President is in the Situation Room.
中方对冯的政治庇护的反应跟我预想的一样
China responded to Feng's asylum exactly the way I predicted.
他们增派了一倍海军前往与那国岛
They're doubling their naval presence off the coast of Yonaguni.
你猜谁被赶出战况室了  你和我  弗兰克
And you know who isn't in the Situation Room? You and I, Frank.
你只盯着眼下一时的得失
You're thinking about where we are
却对情势的发展方向视而不见
instead of where we're headed.
这可不像那个在杰斐逊舞会上
Now that isn't the Catherine Durant
和我共舞华尔兹的凯瑟琳·杜兰特
that I waltzed with at the Jefferson Ball.
她深明大势所趋
She understood potential.
她盯着未来
She had her eyes toward the future.
我对那个凯瑟琳·杜兰特说
I told that Catherine Durant
我们需要她这样的人领导国务院
that we needed her in the State Department.
现在也是如此  真不知她哪去了
We still need her. I wish I knew where she was,
因为她和我眼前这个凯瑟琳·杜兰特
because she is not the Catherine Durant
完全是两种人
sitting in front of me right now.
但我跟你说
But I'll tell you something,
如果她不赶快回来的话
If she doesn't show up soon, well,
那这支华尔兹  我只好独自舞下去了
I'm just gonna have to keep waltzing alone.
因为我已经
Because I am done trying to
不想再去说服我面前的这个女人
convince this woman in front of me
和我携手前行了
to take my arm.
你快忙去吧  我不留你了
Oh, don't let me keep you.
我就在这儿  我哪也不去  弗兰克
I'm here. I'm not going anywhere, Frank.
你现在能拿到总统简报吗
You still have access to the presidential briefing?
能  就在我手上
Yes, I have it right here.
跟我说说与中国之间的全部情况
Walk me through everything that's going on with China.
冯也出场了  也许我们用得上他
Feng is in play now. We might be able to use him.
怎么用
How?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
但显然他在北京眼里是有价值的
But he's clearly valuable to Beijing,
那么他对我们就也有价值
which makes him valuable to us.
从没提起过冯山德吗
Nothing about Xander Feng?
没有
Never.
丹尼尔·拉尼根呢  还有雷蒙德·塔斯克
Daniel Lanagin? Raymond Tusk?
我们只谈了他的婚姻
We only discussed their marriage.
从未涉及白宫的公务
Nothing about the business of the White House.
他可曾间接提起过与工作有关的压力
Any oblique reference to work-related pressures he was feeling?
他说他现在睡眠太少
He said he wasn't getting as much sleep as he'd like.
你给他开过什么药物吗
Did you ever prescribe him any medication?
正如我一贯声称  我只提供宗教咨询
As I've always stated, I provided religious counsel.
我明白  但我问的是药物处方
I understand. But I'm asking about medication.
这有什么关系吗
How is this relevant?
我想查证他的判断力是否因此受影响
I'm trying to assess whether his judgment may have been impaired.
在我看来  他和他的妻子
In my opinion, he and his wife
面对的是典型的婚姻问题
were dealing with standard marital issues.
你这是答非所问  拉金博士
That's not what I asked, Dr. Larkin.
所以我再问第三遍
So I will ask for a third time.
而且问得更明确些
And let me be more specific.
美利坚合众国总统
Was any medication prescribed
在接受你的咨询服务时  你是否提供过
or taken as a result of your counseling session
任何形式的处方或者药物
by the President of the United States?
他的工作能力完全没有受影响
His faculties were operating at a hundred percent,
如果你是想问这个的话
if that's what you're asking.
是不是有政府方面的人和你谈过了
Has anyone from the administration spoken to you?
什么意思
How do you mean?
关于取证  是不是有人找过你  指导过你
About this deposition. Has anyone approached you, coached you?
如果你现在承认  我会将此认定为及时申报
If you tell me now, I will qualify that as a timely declaration.
我不想继续了
I'd like to leave.
总统放弃了他的保密权利
The President waived his privilege.
但我是自愿作证的
But I'm here voluntarily.
拉金博士  一开始你不肯作证
Dr. Larkin, at first you wouldn't talk to me
因为那有违你的道德准则
because it violated your ethical code.
我尊重你的选择
I respect that.
但现在我要问你  作为一个虔诚之人
But let me ask you, as a man of faith
蓄意对我说谎  难道就不违反你的道德准则吗
is deliberately lying to me an exception to that code?
因为你拒绝说出实情的话
Because that is what you're doing
就有作伪证的嫌疑
by refusing to share the truth.
我不明白
I don't understand.
这法案过不了的
It wasn't going to pass.
但你说我们就要争取到足够的支持了
But you said we almost had the votes.
我们需要能完全确定  但实情并非如此
We needed to be a hundred percent solid, and we weren't.
如果法案未能通过  我们的努力就白费了
If the bill failed, that would set us back.
我们必须接受渐进的改革方案
We need to accept incremental reform.
你的口气跟杰姬·夏普一模一样
You sound just like Jackie Sharp.
其实我现在与她合作了
I'm actually working with her now.
她是一个有力的盟友
She's a powerful ally for us to have.
可她那样让我下不来台
After what she did to me?
还公开羞辱你
After what she said about you?
我要是被他人的非议所左右
If I let the things people say about me get under my skin,
我连家门都出不去了
I wouldn't be able to leave my own home.
你知道结果会怎样
You know how this will go.
人人都会说"太好了  我们取得了成功"
Everyone will say, "Great, we did something,"
但其实一无所成
Which is really nothing.
他们会高兴一时  然后就抛诸脑后忘个干净
They'll pat themselves on the back and they'll forget about it.
我们让人们注意这个话题了
We helped put this on the radar.
我以为我们是要真正改变现状
I thought we were doing something real.
改变人们的生活  幼稚死了  对吧
Changing people's lives. How naive, right?
但至少我不愿意放弃
But at least I didn't want to give up.
也许杰姬·夏普说对了
Maybe Jackie Sharp is right.
你他妈就是个懦夫
You are a fucking coward.
是我鼓励你站出来说出你的遭遇
I'm the one that pulled you out from under the covers.
之前你在逃避  靠吃药度日
You were hiding. You and your pills.
编造各种谎言自欺欺人
So you tell yourself whatever you need to.
我失态了
I'm sorry.
有些政治现实  是我们无法忽视的
There were political realities we couldn't ignore.
你想没想过为什么那么多人憎恨华盛顿
Do you ever wonder why so many people hate Washington?
就是因为你这种人说那种屁话
It's because of people like you using phrases like that.
雷蒙德
Raymond?
虽说该开灯  但既然花钱住进
I'd turn the lights on, but when you're paying for the room
风景最好的房间  就不如欣赏个够
with the best view you might as well make the most of it.
我从来没上过顶层  你呢
I've never been in the penthouse here. Have you?
这是什么情况
What's going on?
你知道我为什么来华盛顿吗
Do you know why I'm in D.C.?
没关系  雷米
Oh, it's okay, Remy.
你能说出的话我都已经知道了
There's nothing you can say that I don't already know.
冯要去作证了
Feng is on his way to testify.
不管赛斯跟你说了什么都不要信他
Whatever Seth has told you, don't believe a word of it.
他会说什么我不该相信的事呢
What might he have told me that I shouldn't believe?
你跟副总统见面了
You met with the Vice President.
在一座教堂里  别装作没这回事
In a church. Don't pretend you didn't.
想当墙头草吗
Playing both sides?
雷蒙德  我...
Raymond, look --
我想听你说出来  你跟弗兰克见面了
I want to hear you say it. That you met with Frank.
我会跟你说的  雷蒙德  但他不能在这儿
I'll talk to you, Raymond, but not with him here.
你先出去吧
Leave us.
要我在电梯里等你吗
Should I hold the elevator for you?
滚你妈的
Go fuck yourself.
好  那你走楼梯吧
Okay. You can take the stairs.
他们在耍你  雷蒙德
They're toying with you, Raymond.
没错  但是你也一样  雷米
No doubt. But so are you, Remy.
我是想哄骗弗兰克  让他以为已经安全了
I wanted to lead Frank on, give him a false sense of security.
如果你要说谎  那就说得漂亮点
If you're gonna lie, lie better than that.
他们想离间我们
They want to tear us apart.
你想要多条退路  这我不怪你
I don't blame you for wanting to keep your options open.
但你显然买错了保险
But clearly you have bought the wrong insurance policy.
不要这样搬起石头砸自己的脚
Don't shoot yourself in the foot like this.
你的脚  石头也是你拿着呢
Your foot. And you're holding the gun.
去找个别的地方流血吧
Now go someplace else to bleed.
你想谈谈流血吗
You want to talk about blood?
你与弗兰克的这场战争已经让你流了多少血了
How much have you spilt in this war with Frank?
我做的一切都是为了维护和平
All I've tried to do is keep the peace.
你本可让他占上风
You could've let him have the upper hand.
除了你的自尊  还会让你损失什么
What would that have really cost you, other than your pride?
真遗憾
Such a shame.
你刚刚树立了身家420亿的敌人  雷米
You have just made 42 billion enemies, Remy.
外加一些零头
And some change.
390亿  雷蒙德  你的市值在缩水
39 billion, Raymond. Your market cap is shrinking.
白宫顾问比尔·嘉利克今早被特别检查官
White House Counsel Bill Galich was called into questioning this morning
比尔·嘉利克
希瑟·邓巴传唤质询
by Special Prosecutor Heather Dunbar.
从邓巴办公室得到的消息称
According to Dunbar's office,
他们怀疑
there are suspicions that
嘉利克可能干预了证人证词
Galich may have tampered with witness testimony.
这名证人是托马斯·拉金博士
The witness in question is Dr. Thomas Larkin,
一位牧师与咨询师
a reverend and therapist
据称他为总统和第一夫人进行了
who allegedly conducted secret marriage counseling sessions
秘密婚姻咨询
for the president and first lady.
如果没有来自总统的明确指示
The White House counsel wouldn't be manipulating testimony
白宫顾问是不会去干预证词的
without explicit direction from the Oval Office.
同样让人不安的是  我们的总统
And just as disconcerting is the fact that our president
在寻求心理治疗
is seeking psychological treatment
并且向美国人民隐瞒这一点
and chose to hide this from the American people.
如果在这方面我们无法信任他
If we can't trust him about that,
那我们又怎么知道他是否与洗钱阴谋有关呢
then how do we know he wasn't involved in a money-laundering scheme?
怎么知道他的精神状况适合来领导我们呢
How do we know he's mentally fit to lead?
最重要的是  如果他知法犯法
And most important, how can he enforce the law
又如何维护法律
when he's breaking it?
我认为我们众议院的同事
I believe our colleagues in the House certainly have enough
已经有足够理由考虑弹劾
to consider Articles of Impeachment.
信任与法律都被践踏
Both trust and laws have been broken.
不管众议院作何打算
Whatever the House decides to do,
这位总统必须承担责任
we must hold this president accountable.
全力支持总统
Fully support the president
不管发生什么都跟他站在一起
and will stand by him no matter what comes his way.
揽进来  处理掉  给我找艾拉·萨伊德
Put that in, put it out. Then get me Ayla Sayyad.
至于雷米  让他再多倒霉一阵子吧
And as for Remy, let's let him wither on the vine a little longer.
同时  让他的另一半明天来众议院
In the meantime, have his better half come by the house tomorrow.
雷蒙德
Raymond?
不  杰姬
No. Jackie.
塔斯克先生
Mr. Tusk.
邓巴女士  我活了67年
Well, Ms. Dunbar, in 67 years on this planet
还从来没被传唤过
I have never once been issued a subpoena.
现在总算可以从遗愿清单上划掉了
I can now cross that off my bucket list.
此次会面将被记录和封存
This interview is being recorded and sealed.
如传票所述  塔斯克先生  我与冯山德谈过了
As the subpoena mentioned, Mr. Tusk, I spoke with Xander Feng.
他指证你与他合作  自2005年以来
He verified that you were his partner
将中国资金洗白并流入超级政治行动委员会
in laundering Chinese money to political Super PACs since 2005.
你如何回应他的指控
How would you respond to his allegations?
我的客户要行使宪法第五修正案赋予的权利
My client exercises his right to plead the Fifth Amendment.
你是否曾用这些捐赠来换取政治利益
Did you ever use these contributions to bargain for political favors?
我的客户要行使宪法第五修正案赋予的权利
My client exercises his right to plead the Fifth Amendment.
你跟丹尼尔·拉尼根是什么关系
What was your relationship with Daniel Lanagin?
我的客户要行使宪法第五修正案赋予的权利
My client exercises his right to plead the Fifth Amendment.
我都记不得我为什么要来这儿了
I don't even remember why I came over here.
你是说你最初来我家吗
You mean when you first showed up?
不  我是说来厨房
No. To the kitchen.
很抱歉  别认为我不爱你
I'm sorry. Please don't think that I don't love you --
那是为什么  我不明白
Then why? I don't get it.
一切发展得太快了
Everything's been so fast.
还有
And...
我不知道  很难说清  但我还没准备好
I don't know. It's hard to explain, but I'm not ready for this.
-都是胡说    -不是的
- That's bullshit.   - No, it's not.
我还在努力适应新生活
I'm still trying to figure out this new life.
这一切太让人搞不清
And this is too confusing.
只有这是清清楚楚的  这你知道
This is the only thing that's clear, and you know it.
你在害怕  但这是好事
You're afraid, but it's good to be afraid when you're--
你得离开  为了你自己好
I need you to leave, okay? For your own good.
我只会伤害你
I am just gonna hurt you.
我比你想得坚韧得多
I have thicker skin than you can even imagine.
别把事情搞得太痛苦
Please don't make this harder than it has to be.
昨天一切都还好好的  这么突然
Everything was fine yesterday. It's so sudden.
简直莫名其妙
It's like it's coming out of nowhere.
不是这样  我已经考虑了一段时间了
Well, it's not. I've been thinking about it for a while.
你没有  否则我会察觉的
No, you haven't. I would have sensed it.
能不能请你  拜托你走就是了
Would you please, please, please just go?
告诉我发生了什么事
Just tell me what's going on.
我不指望你会理解
I don't expect you to understand.
也许你可以试着...
Well, maybe if you try --
我不想让你待在这儿  好吗
I don't want you here. Okay?
我不像你爱我那样爱着你
I don't love you the way that you love me.
只是利用你  因为有你陪着感觉很好
I was using you because it felt good to have you around,
但那样很自私
but it was selfish.
我说那些话  因为我知道你爱听
I said the words because I knew you wanted to hear 'em,
但我不是真心的
but I didn't mean 'em.
我不想继续说下去了
And I don't want to keep saying 'em.
我出去走一会儿  你收拾东西吧
I'm gonna go for a walk while you pack your stuff.
不  我不要这儿的任何东西
No. I don't want anything that's been here.
丽萨
Lisa...?
"四面的山洼雾气氤氲
"There was a steaming mist in all the hollows,
凄凉地往山顶涌动
and it roamed in its forlornness up the hill,
双城记
仿佛是个邪恶的精灵  寻找歇脚之地而不得
like an evil spirit, seeking rest and finding none.
那雾粘乎乎的  冰寒彻骨
A clammy, and intensely cold mist,
缓缓地在空中波浪式地翻滚
it made it its slow way through the air in ripples
一浪一浪清晰可见  然后宛如污浊的海涛
that visibly followed and overspread one another,
搞定了
彼此渗诱  融合成了一片
as the waves of an unwholesome sea might do.
雾很浓  车灯几乎
It was dense enough to shut out everything
什么也照不见"
from the light of the coach lamps."
很惊讶你想和我聊聊
I'm surprised you wanted to speak to me.
我并不是很受政府欢迎
I haven't been the biggest friend of the administration.
难道不是找你谈话的最佳理由吗
Isn't that the very best reason to speak with you?
我想开始录音
I'd like to begin recording.
请便
By all means.
许多政治分析家预测
A number of political analysts predict
众议院司法委员会
that the House Judiciary Committee
将就弹劾条款开始听证会
will commence with hearings on Articles of Impeachment.
先就此打住
Let's just stop right there.
你说的这些分析家
So these analysts you speak of,
他们在邓巴的报告发表前就做出预测
they're making predictions prior to Dunbar's report even being released.
报告出来可能得好几个月
That could take months.
司法委员会绝不会等那么久的
There's no way the Judiciary will sit on this for that long.
这不正是听证会的根本问题吗
And isn't that the fundamental flaw with these hearings?
因为包括你在内的媒体记者提出的假设
The committee feels compelled to act because of hypotheses
委员会觉得必须采取行动
advanced by those in the media, such as yourself.
我不能代表我所有的同行  但我只是报道事实
I can't speak for all of my colleagues, but I'm just reporting facts.
你可能会说这是事实  但实话说
Well, you may call them facts, but if we're being honest,
-难道不是    -每篇文章和采访中
- aren't they just --   - In every article and interview,
我都只是提出怀疑
I report alleged activities.
怀疑重复的次数够多
And if you repeat allegations enough,
一遍一遍  反反复复
again and over and over and over,
那就三人成虎了  这是人之常情
people start to believe that they're true. That's human nature.
我做过调查
I've done my research.
冯山德已经承认洗钱
Xander Feng admitted to the money laundering.
但你已经不报道冯山德了  对吗
But you're no longer writing about Xander Feng. Are you?
你现在报道政府
You're writing about the administration.
事实上  听证会就是由媒体报道引发的
The truth is, these hearings have been initiated by the press.
我担心的是总统会遭到媒体的审判
And my fear is that the president will be tried by the press.
你相信他是无罪的吗
Do you believe he's innocent?
绝对
Absolutely.
我在书面声明中这么写  我现在也还要这么说
I said so in my written statement and I say so again now.
白宫的法律顾问已经否认了干预拉金博士的证词
The White House counsel has denied coaching Dr. Larkin,
-但根据...    -不管最终发现了什么
- but according to Ms. --   - Whatever comes to light,
都只会证明总统的清白
it will only prove the president's innocence.
我告诉你为什么  加勒特·沃克是我所认识的
And I'll tell you why. I have never known anyone more honest,
最诚实  正直  爱国的人
ethical, and patriotic than Garrett Walker.
他对我国宪法和法律的尊重
His reverence for the Constitution and the laws of this country
无人能及
are surpassed by none.
特莉莎和我有幸拥有一段坚固忠诚的婚姻
Tricia and I have been blessed with a strong and loving marriage.
但再坚固的婚姻也会面临挑战
But even strong marriages face challenges.
就像成百万的美国人一样
Like millions of Americans,
我们向一位宗教导师寻求建议
we sought counseling from a spiritual advisor,
而他恰好也是一位职业治疗师
one who happened also to be a professional therapist.
多年来我们经常
Over the years we have often
在困境中向我们的信仰寻求帮助
turned to our faith in times of adversity.
很多人批评我们
Many have criticized us.
但你们宁愿要一位不去寻求帮助的总统吗
But would you rather have a president that doesn't ask for help?
我每一天都会请我妻子帮我
I ask for help from my wife every day.
我们相扶相依已经有23年了
We've relied on one another for 23 years.
我们一起养育了两个漂亮的孩子
We've raised two beautiful children together.
华尔街电讯报  副总统维护总统
一起走过了竞选之旅
Endured the campaign trails together.
从州首府丹佛
From the state capital in Denver
一路来到国家首都
to the nation's capital,
我们一直都在彼此身边
we've always been at each other's side.
我嫁给这个人的原因
I married this man for the
和你们很多人选他的原因一样
same reason that so many of you voted for him.
因为他是一位信徒  因为他热爱家人
Because he's a man of God. Because he believes in family.
因为他有同情心和爱心
Because he is compassionate and loving.
人无完人
Now, none of us are perfect.
我不是  特莉莎也不是
I'm not. Tricia's not.
尽管她很接近完美了
Although she certainly comes close.
早上好  冯先生
Good morning, Mr. Feng.
我不会否认我作为凡人的极限
I won't ignore what makes me human.
否则只是盲目
That's a form of blindness.
好的领导者应该正视自己的缺点
Good leadership means tackling my imperfections head on.
对一个在逃亡的人来说不错嘛
Not bad for a man on the run.
你是说对一个有豁免权的人来说
You mean a man with immunity.
随便你想怎么说了
Wherever you're most comfortable.
我们有很多事要谈
We have a lot to discuss.
我是在了解情况的前提下这么做的
I do so with open eyes.
我的爱也是明明白白的
Just as I love, with open eyes,
爱我的妻子  爱上帝
my wife, my maker,
爱我的国家
and my country.
请进
Come in.
谢谢  密查姆
Thank you, Meechum.
杰姬  一般来说
Jackie, in these circumstances
我会去找你
normally I would come to you,
但现在我们还是保持距离为好
but we need to keep a public distance for the time being.
我以为我是来讨论性侵法案的
I thought I was here to discuss the sexual assault bill.
是的  还有其他的事
You are. Among other things.
明白了
I see.
你有条件
There's a price.
不要这样说
Well, we don't think of it that way.
不管今天你说什么
I'm going to support your bill,
我都会支持你的法案
no matter what you say today.
什么事
Regarding?
弹劾
Impeachment.
如果事情真闹到司法委员会
Well, if it goes to the Judiciary --
几乎肯定是会的
It most definitely will.
我不那么肯定
I'm not sure about that.
你们看了总统的声明了吗
Did you see the president's address?
我们看了
We did.
我觉得能起些作用  控制事态
I think it will help. Stop the bleeding.
而且弹劾可以被否决
Impeachment can be defeated.
但那是我们要避免的
But that's we need to avoid.
你希望弹劾
You want impeachment...
为什么要打一场明知会输的仗
Why fight a losing battle?
我们在众议院是多数党
We have a majority in the House.
现在是
We do now.
但如果本党不能和一个污点总统
But if this party fails to distance itself
划清界限
from a toxic president...
我们在做长远打算
We're thinking ahead here.
所以我才会找你就法案的事和解
It's why I came to you about the bill.
我们不值得为它翻脸
Because it wasn't worth burning a bridge over.
长远来讲  我们合作的好处更多
In the long run we have a lot more to gain by working together.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你在《电讯报》采访的时候说你会
You said in the Telegraph article that you would sta--
我必须那么说
I had to.
我的办公室跟总统的只隔了三间屋子
My office is three doors down from the president's.
我不能公开诋毁他
I can't publicly deride him.
你希望我来做
You want me to do it?
我们希望你做你最拿手的  拉选票
We want you to do what you do so well: whip the votes.
我不能背叛总统
I can't abandon the president.
如果这个党救了他
If the party rescues him,
我们将在中期选举时失去50个席位
we'll lose 50 seats in the House in the midterms.
你会失去你在领导层的地位
You will lose your position in the leadership.
我们要花十年
And it will take us a decade
重新赢得选民的信任
to regain the trust of the electorate.
我们只求你肯听取意见
All we're asking is that you have an open mind.
克莱尔就是如此
Claire kept an open mind,
你得以修改性侵法案
and you'll pass sexual assault reform as a result.
你不能把弹劾和...
You can't possibly compare impeachment to --
只是举个例子  杰姬
It's an illustration, Jackie.
说明未来会怎么样
Of what the future looks like.
我们提出的  是进步
What we offer is progress.
并保证日后还会有更多进步
With a promise of more to come.
这只是个开始  杰姬
It's only the beginning, Jackie.
坚决  务实  记得吗
Ruthless pragmatism, remember?
所以我才选你做党鞭
That's why I wanted you to be the whip.
我们三个是同一类人
The three of us, we're cut from the same cloth.
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President,
你要我做的  几乎是叛国
what you're asking is just shy of treason.
几乎  也就是政治
Just shy. Which is politics.
小心  那很易碎
Be careful. It's delicate.
这是什么
What is it?
一件我做了很久的事
Something I've been working on for a very long time.
马上就要完成了
And it's nearly finished.
杰姬
Jackie?
帮我们完成吧
Help us finish it.
■
美国法律规定  在总统或其他政府要员  联邦法官
出现重大工作失误  或有严重违法嫌疑时
国会有权行使弹劾权力  弹劾程序启动后
首先要求众议院投票  简单多数通过弹劾决议后
再由参议院进行表决
但是只有在参议院2/3的多数投赞成票后
弹劾才会生效
以防止两党以弹劾作为政治斗争的武器
■
虽然美国历史上许多总统在任期间曾爆出丑闻
但是国会真正启动弹劾程序只有两次
1868年  国会以违反行政任命法为由
投票弹劾时任总统安德鲁·杰克逊
但是在参议院投票时  一票之差
弹劾案没有获得所需的2/3多数
第二次弹劾程序启动要等到一百多年之后
在上世纪90年代  总统克林顿深陷莱温斯基丑闻
在国会占有多数席位的共和党启动弹劾程序
但是同样没有获得足够票数  克林顿涉险过关
由于他任职期间美国经济高速发展
所以虽然丑闻缠身  但是克林顿民意支持率一直很高
在人们所熟知的水门事件中  没有启动弹劾程序
在国会考虑进行弹劾前  尼克松总统便已经宣布辞职